也不必害怕黑暗中流行的瘟疫
Nor for the pestilence that walketh in darkness.
或是在正午把人毁灭的毒病
Nor for the destruction that wasteth at noonday.
愿主与我同在  在我需要之时
Be with me Lord, in my hour of need.
耶和华是我的避难所
Because thou hast made the Lord, which is my refuge,
你已将至高者当你的居所
even the most high, thy habitation.
愿主与我同在  在我需要之时
Be with me Lord, in my hour of need.
祸患必不临到你
There shall no evil befall thee,
灾害也不挨近你的帐棚
neither shall any plague come nigh thy dwelling.
愿主与我同在  在我需要之时
Be with me Lord, in my hour of need.
因他要为你吩咐他的使者
For he shall give his angels charge over thee,
在你行的一切道路上保护你
to keep thee in all thy ways.
愿主与我同在  在我需要之时
Be with me Lord, in my hour of need.
我们休息一下吧
Let's take a little break, shall we?
亲爱的  你还好吗
Hon, are you feeling all right?
嗯  我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
我都记不清上次这种情况是什么时候的事了
I just can't remember one quite like this.
他应该去睡一会儿
He should try and get some sleep.
嗯  走吧
Yeah. Here you go.
我带他去吧  格拉策尔先生
Oh, I'll take him, Mr. Glatzel.
来
Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
-谢谢你  阿尔尼  -没事  来  小家伙
- Thank you, Arne. - No problem. Come on, buddy.
他受不了继续这样下去了
He can't take much more of this.
他不用继续这样了
He won't have to.
驱魔已经获得批准  接下来进展会很快
Things will move quickly now that the exorcism's been approved.
戈登神父已经在来的路上了
Father Gordon's already on his way.
你是一个很勇敢的孩子  你知道吗
You're one brave kid, you know?
我小时候个子比较矮
I was a little runt growing up,
所以我知道经常被欺负的滋味
so I know what it's like to be picked on.
但是
But...
这和你现在的遭遇比起来根本不算什么
But that was nothing compared to what you're going through.
我不觉得自己很勇敢
I don't feel very brave.
勇敢并不代表不害怕
Being brave doesn't mean you're not scared.
而是说明你虽然害怕  但仍然坚持住了
It means you are scared but you hang in there.
会没事的
It's gonna be all right.
我不会让你出任何事的
I won't let anything happen to you.
我保证
I promise.
阿尔尼  你打算什么时候向我姐姐求婚
Arne. When are you gonna ask my sister to marry you?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
-少来  -真的  我...
- Come on. - No, I don't, I...
不  救命
No! Help me!
不  不  不  不
No, no, no! No, no, no!
-戴维  -戴维  他在哪里
- David! - David! Where is he?
戴维
David!
发生了什么  孩子  你没事吧
What's happening, buddy? Are you okay?
戴维  怎么了
David, what's going on?
戴维
David?
不
No!
神父  我们得赶紧开始
Father, we need to do this, right now!
好  把他抱上车
Okay, let's get him down to the car
我们送他去教堂
and we'll drive him to the church.
不  神父  就在这里
No, Father. Right now.
不  不  不
No! No! No!
抓住他的手臂  别放手
Grab his arms, don't let go.
我的上帝啊  求你拯救这倚靠你的仆人
Save your servant who trusts in you, my God.
主啊  在他周围
Let him find in you, Lord,
筑起抵御敌人的堡垒
a fortified tower in the face of the enemy.
要穿戴神所赐的全副军装
Put on the full armor of God,
就能抵挡魔鬼的诡计
that ye may be able to stand against the wiles of the devil.
抵抗世界的黑暗之力
Against the powers of the darkness of this world.
抵抗邪恶
Against wickedness.
洛琳  怎么了
Lorraine, what's wrong?
我没事
I'm fine.
洛琳
Lorraine.
愿主从圣所救助他
Lord! Send him aid from your Holy place
从锡安坚固他
and watch over him from Sion.
主啊  听我的祷告
Lord, heed my prayer.
主啊
Lord!
不  神父
No. Father!
神父
Father!
你们的急救包呢
Where's your first aid kit?
-在厨房里  -我去拿
- It's in the kitchen! - I'm on it!
艾德  快点
Ed, hurry up!
快点  艾德
Hurry, Ed!
怪物
Monster.
艾德  艾德  快点
Ed. Ed, Hurry!
没有用
It's not working!
什么  戴维  等等
What? David, wait!
停下  怎么回事  怎么回事
Stop it! What? What?
戴维  戴维  帮帮我
David! David! Help me, please!
你在干什么  戴维
What are you doing? David!
救救他  求你了
Help him, please!
戴维  停下  戴维  戴维
David, stop it! David! David!
-别缠着他  -阿尔尼  别和它对话
- Leave him alone! - Arne, don't talk to it.
我说  别缠着他  他只是个小男孩  懦夫
I said, leave him alone. He's just a little boy, you coward!
不  阿尔尼  别和它对话
No, Arne, don't talk to it!
我要让你的心停止跳动  老家伙
I'll stop your heart, old man.
艾德
Ed!
听我说  看着我
Listen to me. Look at me.
看着我  我知道你还在  戴维
Look at me. I know you're still in there, David.
别缠着他了
Just leave him alone, okay?
别缠着他  冲我来
Leave him alone and take me.
冲我来
Take me.
冲我来  冲我来啊
Hey, take me. Take me!
戴维
David!
不要动他  来找我
Leave him alone and take me!
不
No.
不  不
No, no.
戴维  戴维  戴维
David. David, David!
戴维  你没事吧
David, are you okay?
戴维  来妈妈这
David, go with Mom.
戴维
Yes, David.
艾德  艾德  亲爱的
Ed? Ed! Hon!
怎么了
What?
-赶紧打急救电话  -好
- Somebody call 911! - Okay.
对八岁男孩戴维·格拉策尔的驱魔仪式原本是要结束他几个月来遭受的折磨
但是对于阿尔尼·约翰逊来说  一切才刚刚开始  接下来发生的一系列惨剧轰动了全美国
对八岁男孩戴维· 也导致了沃伦夫妇职业生涯中最邪恶的发现
《招魂3：鬼使神差》
沃伦太太
Mrs. Warren.
他的情况稳定了
He's stabilized.
我们要把他转移到心内科病房
We're gonna transfer him to the coronary unit.
-所以他是心脏病发吗  -是的
- So, it was a heart attack? - Yes.
而且恐怕还挺严重
And not a minor one, I'm afraid.
-我们现在能看看他吗  -还不行
- Can we see him now? - Not yet.
我们要在他的动脉里植入支架
We're gonna to put a stent into his artery,
尽力帮助他血液流回心脏
try to get blood flowing back to his heart.
那他会没事吗
So, is he gonna be all right?
我们得先做一些测试
We're gonna need to run a few more tests
我才能给你们肯定的答复
before I'm comfortable answering that.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
-别缠着他  -阿尔尼  别和它对话
- Leave him alone! - Arne, don't talk to it.
别缠着他  冲我来
Leave him alone and take me.
别缠着他
Leave him alone!
木乃伊终于活了
Hey, the mummy lives.
你为什么让我睡到现在
Hey, why did you let me sleep so late?
不是我让你睡的  我根本叫不醒你
I didn't let you, I couldn't wake you.
-你叫不醒我  -是啊  叫不醒
- You couldn't wake me? - No, I couldn't.
那可真奇怪
Oh, that's strange.
你肯定不够努力
You mustn't have been trying very hard.
是啊
No.
-冷静点  冷静点  -布鲁诺就在外面呢
- Buddy! Easy, easy, easy! - Okay, Bruno is right outside.
拜托  布鲁诺见得多了  他才不介意
Oh, come on. Bruno's a worldly man, he doesn't care.
不
No.
不  等等  我其实真有话要问你
No, no, wait. Actually, I do want to ask you something.
好吧  你想问什么
Okay. What do you want to ask me?
不是什么大事
It's no big deal.
我...我一直在想
I've... I've been thinking...
现在戴维也没事了
And now David's out of the woods,
也许我们应该把这一切抛到脑后
maybe we should put all this behind us
离开这个地方
and get out of this place.
-怎么样  -你是指离开布鲁克菲尔德吗
- You know? - You mean, leave Brookfield?
是啊  为什么不呢  这里没什么好留恋的了
Sure, why not? We've got nothing keeping us here now. Do we?
是啊  只除了我的家人
Oh, yeah. Nothing but my family
而且我们没有钱  阿尔尼
and all the money we don't have. Arne--
好吧  钱不是什么大问题
Okay, well, money's no big deal, right?
我们都有工作
We're both working,
这地方又不需要我们花钱
and this place doesn't cost us anything.
阿尔尼  我才刚开始这份工作
Arne, I just started this job.
不能就这么一走了之
I can't just up and walk out now.
-老天啊  -再说了 布鲁诺根本不知道
- Jesus Christ! - And besides, Bruno doesn't know
该怎么照顾这些狗狗
the first thing about taking care of these dogs.
让我好好考虑一下  好吗
Let me think about it. Okay?
-你会考虑吗  -嗯  我会考虑
- You'll think about it? - Yeah, I'll think about it.
好  好的
Okay. There we go.
好了  换衣服吧
Okay, get dressed.
我爱你
I love you.
我觉得戴维肯定会喜欢的
I think David will love that.
-你联系我妈妈了吗  -是的
- Did you call my mom? - Yeah, I did.
-我和她说了我们会迟到  -好的  谢谢
- I told her we were going to be very late. - Okay, thank you.
不  阿尔尼  别吃了  别吃了
No, Arne. Please stop eating, please stop.
哈斯基特太太  见到你很高兴  谢谢你过来
Mrs. Haskett, so good to see you, thanks for coming by.
-我们要出去了  -再见  波奇
- Hey, we're headed out now. - Bye, Pookie.
我写下了在我们离开期间你要做的事
I wrote down a list of stuff for you to do while we're gone.
安排这些工作
Oh, keeping track of this stuff
是我花钱雇你做的
is what I'm supposed to be paying you for.
周末可不算
Not on weekends, you're not.
我都让你免费住在这里了
I'm letting you live here rent free.
这应该能包含周末了  也许还能包含节假日
That should buy me the weekends maybe the holidays, too.
好了  安迪一杯  其他狗狗两杯
Okay, Andy gets one cup, everyone else gets two.
魔魔和火花会被接走
Magic and Sparky are getting picked up,
所以不用担心它们
so you don't need to worry about them.
不过今天下午你还得找个时间
But, you'll have to take everyone else outside
把所有狗都遛了
at some point this afternoon.
露比对蜜蜂过敏
Ruby's allergic to bees,
万一它被蜜蜂蛰了  你得打给急救兽医
if she gets stung you've got to call the emergency vet.
我把号码写下来贴在冰箱上了
I wrote the number down and stuck it on the fridge.
阿尔尼  想轻松赚五块钱吗
Arne, you wanna make a quick five bucks, man?
我的音响坏了
My stereo's busted.
好啊  我晚点看看  不过得收十五块
Yeah, sure. I'll take a look at it later. But, make it 15.
十块
Ten.
-今早真是...  -我知道
- ...what happened this morning. - I know.
妈  好了  请别说出去
Ma, okay. Please don't say anything.
我不会说的  我保证
I won't say anything, I promise.
好吧  就是...
Okay, just...
他问我能不能和他一起离开布鲁克菲尔德
He asked if we could leave Brookfield.
-你懂他是什么意思吧  -不懂
- You know what that means, don't you? - No.
-你是说他向你求婚了  -不算是
- Actually, you mean he proposed? - Not exactly.
-你答应他了吗  -还没有
- Did you say, yes? - Not exactly.
阿尔尼  你能把盛着肉的盘子端出来吗
Arne! Can you bring out the tray with the meat on it?
好的  我都饿死了  你饿不饿
Oh, yes. I'm starving! Are you starving, bud?
饿
Yeah.
好  我去拿肉
Okay, I'll go get the meat.
(布鲁克菲尔德综合医院  急诊室)
梅里克医生  请到六号手术室
Doctor Merrick, to OR-6.
真高兴能再见到朱迪
It was nice seeing Judy again.
她会待很久吗
Will she be staying long?
我不知道  要看情况...
I don't know, um, it depends if...
护士说你这几天都在这椅子上睡觉
The nurse says that you have been sleeping in that chair.
你回家休息一会  艾德会理解的
Ed would understand if you went home for a little while.
我有没有跟你讲过我们是怎么认识的
Did I ever tell you the story of how we met?
好像没有
No, I don't think so.
只说了是高中时期的青春情愫  对吗
Just that you were young. In high school, wasn't it?
是的  那时我们十七岁
Yeah. We were 17.
(白杨电影院)
我和闺蜜们出去玩
I went out with my girlfriends and...
我们去看电影  他是电影院的引座员
And he was an usher at the movie theater that we went to.
看完电影后
Afterwards...
我们出去吃冰淇淋
we went out for ice cream.
他带我去公园  没想到下起了雨
He took me out to the park, but then it started to rain.
我们站在凉亭下躲雨  直到雨停
And we stood under the gazebo until it stopped.
转眼三十年过去了
That was 30 years ago.
我可以回我们的房子去  神父
I could go back to the house, Father,
但他在哪  家就在哪
but my home is here with him.
天呐  阿尔尼  你在搞什么
Jesus Christ, Arne! What the hell?
能不能让它们消停消停
Can we please do something about this racket?
这些狗吠得我要发疯了
These dogs are driving me crazy!
它们可能闻到兔子或什么的了
They probably just smell a rabbit or something.
-你怎么没上班  -我有点不舒服
- How come you're not at work? - I wasn't feeling so hot.
阿尔尼  你来得正是时候
Arne! Perfect timing, man.
进来陪我喝杯啤酒吧
Why don't you come inside with me, have a beer.
要是能把音响修好  就能挂牌关门休息了
If we get that stereo fixed we can put up a sign, close up shop.
-我觉得还是算了  布鲁诺  -别这样
- You know what, I don't think so, Bruno. - Come on.
-怎么  你戒酒了  -不是  我就是不...
- Why, you quit drinking? - No, I just don't--
这么着  下周六我们再一起戒酒
Tell you what, we can both quit next Saturday.
怎么样
How about that?
洛琳  洛琳
Lorraine. Lorraine.
-洛琳  -爸爸
- Lorraine. - Daddy!
艾德  谢天谢地
Ed, thank God.
洛琳
Lorraine.
-你得联系格拉策尔家  -她刚打来了  没事了...
- You have to call the Glatzels. - She just called, you're fine--
我们得警告他们  那个孩子被它附身了
We have to warn them, it's got the kid.
不  没事了  结束了
No, it's fine, it's over.
戴维安全了  恶魔已经消散了
David is safe, the demon is gone.
是阿尔尼  阿尔尼被附身了
Arne. It's got Arne!
真厉害  干得漂亮
It's beautiful, man. Nicely done!
来  别让我一个人喝闷酒
Come on, man, don't make me drink alone.
你女朋友会觉得我是个酒鬼的
Your girl's gonna think I'm a drunk.
你知道...
Do you know...
我在悉尼看过这些人的演唱会吗
that I saw these guys play in Sydney?
他们差点没把女王剧院的顶给掀翻
They nearly blew the roof off Her Majesty's Theater!
布鲁诺  能把声音关小点吗
Bruno! Can you turn that down?
我是在测试他修得怎么样
I'm testing out his work!
怎么了  你没事吧  布鲁诺
What's the matter? Are you okay? Bruno--
-来跳舞  兄弟  -布鲁诺  不  别闹了
- Let's dance, brother! - Bruno! No, stop!
布鲁诺  布鲁诺  我的天呐
Bruno. Bruno! Oh, my Lord...
好了  布鲁诺  睡觉觉吧
Okay. Bruno, go night-night.
-不  先跳舞  -不跳了
- No! Not until we dance. - Yes! No, we're not dancing.
-就跳一支  一支  -我不想跳舞  布鲁诺
- One dance! One dance! - I don't want to dance! Bruno!
好吧  就一支舞
Okay, one dance.
-我是托马斯警官  -我叫洛琳·沃伦
- This is Officer Thomas. - My name is Lorraine Warren.
我知道这么说你会觉得我疯了
I know how this is going to sound,
但在布鲁克菲尔德寄养犬舍
but there's going to be a tragedy
即将发生一起惨案
at the Brookfield Boarding Kennels.
黛比
Debbie!
-阿尔尼  -布鲁诺
- Arne... - Bruno?
不  住手
No, stop.
阿尔尼
Arne!
布鲁诺  住手
Bruno, stop!
阿尔尼  救救我
Arne, help me.
阿尔尼  怎么了
Arne. What is going on?
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
阿尔尼  住手
Arne, please stop it!
宝贝
Baby?
怎么了
What the hell?
不  住手
No, stop!
你还好吗
You okay there?
你没事吧
You okay?
站在原地别动  好吗  不要动
Now, you just stay right there, okay? Don't move.
我可能伤了人
I think I hurt someone.
我是托马斯警司
This is Sergeant Thomas.
发现一名受害者倒地  有多处捅伤
I have one victim down, multiple stab wounds.
今日下午  布鲁诺·索尔斯在光天化日之下被谋杀
Residents of Brookfield were shocked this afternoon
布鲁克菲尔德市民惊恐万分
by the broad daylight murder of Bruno Sauls.
索尔斯是当地一家犬舍的经理
Sauls, the manager of a local dog kennel,
他被捅了二十二刀
was stabbed 22 times.
该市建市193年来首次发生谋杀
This is the first murder in that town's 193-year history.
谁能登耶和华的山
Who shall ascend into the hill of the Lord?
谁能站在祂的圣所
Or who shall stand in his holy place?
就是手洁心清
He that hath clean hands, and a pure heart,
不向虚妄
who hath not lifted up his soul unto vanity,
起誓不怀诡诈的人
nor sworn deceitfully.
他必蒙耶和华赐福
He shall receive the blessing from the Lord,
又蒙救他的神使他成义
and righteousness from the God of his salvation.
好  可以了
Right. That's enough.
谢谢你
Thank you.
怎么样
Well?
这些宗教物品本来足以
These religious objects would've been enough
激怒一个恶灵
to provoke an inhuman spirit,
如果它确实存在的话
if there was one present.
这是不是说明他没有被附身
Does that mean he's not possessed?
他能诵读圣经可以证明这点
The fact that he can read from the Bible just seals it.
那这是什么意思
So, what does this mean, then...
我只是疯了吗
I'm just crazy?
你现在没有被附身
Well... you're not possessed.
但不代表你之前没有
But that doesn't mean that you weren't.
我主动叫恶魔进入我体内
I... invited this thing into me,
这就是他死去的原因
and that's the reason that he's dead.
所以  无论我受到什么惩罚
So, you know, whatever happens to me,
都是我自找的
I've got it coming.
不是的
No, you don't.
听着
Look...
当时我也在场
I was there.
不管这是怎么回事
Whatever is going on...
不管那天发生了什么
whatever happened that day...
都不是阿尔尼干的
that was not Arne.
我们会竭尽所能帮你
We're going to help you in every way that we can.
如果恶魔已经离开  你们现在还能做什么
If the demon's gone, what can you do now?
你的律师是谁
Who's your lawyer?
他被发现时  全身沾满了受害者的血
He was found covered in the victim's blood.
凶器也是他的
The murder weapon belongs to him
上面沾满他的指纹
and it's got his fingerprints all over it.
没有人质疑这些
Nobody's disputing any of that.
阿尔尼知道他要进监狱了
Arne knows that he's going to prison.
我们只是说有可以减轻处罚的情节
All we're saying is that there were mitigating circumstances.
可以减轻处罚的情节
Mitigating circumstances?
我也觉得他不该被判处死刑
Look, I don't think he should get the death sentence, either.
但我不会在陪审团前
But I am not going before a grand jury
说他是被恶魔附身了
and saying he was possessed by demons.
没有这样的先例
It's never been done.
有过的  英格兰有过两起这样的案例
Yes it has! It's been done twice in England.
迈克尔·泰勒案就是几年前的事
The Michael Taylor case was just a few years ago.
我换个措辞  之前从未有过这样申辩成功的案例
Let me rephrase that. It's never been done successfully.
那就让我们帮助你
Then let us help you.
艾德和我已经
Ed and I have proven the
无数次证明过恶魔的存在
existence of the demonic hundreds of times.
那是对教会  这是法庭
You've proven it to the church. This is a court of law.
证据的标准完全不同
The standards of evidence are completely different.
证人每次上庭前都要向上帝发誓所述为实
The courts accepts the existence of God
所以法庭是承认上帝的存在的
every time a witness swears to tell the truth.
我想现在是时候让他们承认恶魔也存在了
I think it's about time they accept the existence of the devil.
你们连我都说服不了
How are you going to convince a jury
怎么说服陪审团
if you can't even convince me?
这样  你来我们家吃晚餐
I'll tell you what. You come over to our house for dinner.
看看我们这些年收集的证据
We'll show you the evidence we've collected over the years.
我们介绍你认识安娜贝尔
Introduce you to Annabelle.
如果那样你还不相信  我们就不再插手
If you're not convinced, we'll butt out.
可以吗
Deal?
好吧  有什么都拿出来吧
All right. Show me what you got.
约翰逊先生
Mr. Johnson,
案件编号SAJ1216
to count one of indictment number S-A-J-1-2-1-6,
起诉你犯有一级谋杀罪
which charges you with first-degree murder,
A级重罪
a class-A felony,
你认罪吗
how do you plead?
法官阁下  我的委托人不认罪
Your Honor, my client pleads not guilty
抗辩理由是恶魔附身
by reason of demonic possession.
这太胡闹了  我自己能下楼梯
This is ridiculous. I can walk down a flight of stairs.
别说了  你都不应该下床
Oh, hush. You shouldn't even be out of bed.
洛琳
Lorraine.
我刚跟地检办公室的一个朋友谈了
I just talked to a friend of mine in the prosecutor's office.
他会主张判死刑
He's gonna go for the death penalty.
我会进行辩护  但那个孩子是生是死
I'll build the case, but that kid is gonna either live or die
取决于你们两个能发现什么
depending on what you two find.
我们不会让他失望的
Well, we won't let him down.
希望如此
I hope not.
保持联系
Keep me posted.
现在怎么办
So, what now?
我们以前从不需要在附身发生后作出证明
We've never had to prove a possession after the fact.
恶魔不会就这样消失
Demons don't just disappear like this.
还有什么细节
There's something else going on here,
第一次被我们忽视了
something that we missed the first time.
我们从哪开始
Where do we start?
从一开始
At the beginning.
今天是1981年7月18日
It's July 18th, 1981.
我是艾德·沃伦  在场的还有洛琳
This is Ed Warren, here with Lorraine...
朱迪·格拉策尔  黛博拉·格拉策尔
and Judy Glatzel, Deborah Glatzel,
戴维·格拉策尔和阿尔尼·约翰逊
David Glatzel and Arne Johnson.
好了  开始吧
All right, let's get started.
戴维第一次出现这种行为时谁在场
Who was there when David first started exhibiting this behavior?
我们都在  那是我们搬进去那天
We all were. It was the day we moved in.
去吧  玩得开心
There you go. Go have fun with them.
(五个月前)
-想订披萨吗  -好啊  我现在就订
- Wanna order some pizza? - Yeah sure, I'll do that right now.
先把那箱子放下
Put that box down a second.
-为什么  -我只是...
- Why? - I just...
你要干什么
What are you doing?
-看看...  -怎么了  阿尔尼
- Have a look... - What is... Arne!
你知道结婚时才应该新娘抱吧
You know you're supposed to do this when you get married?
好吧  说不定我们也会结婚
Okay, so maybe we'll do that too.
不
No!
妈妈
Mom!
我不知道发生了什么
I didn't know what happened.
就像一场梦
It was like a dream.
我跟别人说的时候  没人相信我
And nobody believed me when I told them.
但那是我第一次看见它
But that was the first time I saw it.
我不明白
I don't get it.
他怎么会邀请了一个恶魔
How could he have invited a demon?
他才进来了几分钟
He was only in here for a few minutes.
这里什么东西都没有呢
There wasn't even anything in here.
那张水床本来放在哪
Where was the water bed?
地毯的位置
Where that rug is.
床垫爆掉的时候把地板泡坏了
The wood got damaged when the mattress ruptured.
-我能看一下吗  -请便
- Mind if I have a look? - Please.
那不是水渍
That's not water damage.
亲爱的  能让我来吗
Hon, will you let me handle this?
你如果钻进去  会把裙子弄脏的
You're going to ruin your dress if you go in there.
客房在十五英尺处  右手边
So, um, the guest room's about 15 feet in and to the right.
好的
Okay.
-小心点  -拿着我的包
- Just be careful. - Just hold my purse.
洛琳  你没事吧
Lorraine! Are you all right?
我没事  艾德  一只老鼠而已
Yeah, I'm fine, Ed. It's just a rat.
这是一个女巫图腾
It's a witch's totem,
是撒旦崇拜者在仪式中使用的
used by Satanists in their rituals.
记得我跟你说过
Remember how I told you
恶灵需要被邀请吗
that an inhuman spirit needs to be invited?
你当时还想不通戴维怎么会做到
And you couldn't imagine how David could do that?
你是对的  不是他邀请的
Well, you were right, he didn't.
我们认为戴维被诅咒了
We think David was cursed.
在驱魔那一晚
And on the night of the exorcism,
诅咒从戴维传到了阿尔尼身上
the curse was passed from David into Arne.
诅咒
Cursed?
你是说这是有人故意做的吗
Are you saying someone did this to us... on purpose?
我们听说过类似的撒旦仪式
We've heard of satanic rituals like this.
恶魔被召唤出来
The demon is summoned,
被附身的个体夺走一条性命后  恶魔就会离开
the possessed individual takes a life and the demon departs.
所以阿尔尼事后能诵读《圣经》
Which is why Arne was able to read from the Bible afterwards.
对  我们认为诅咒戴维的人就是用这个召唤出恶魔
Yeah. We think whoever cursed David, used this to draw the demon.
我们希望你们能向所有警局
And we'd like you to start mailing these out
寄出这些照片
to every police department you can find.
先从本地的开始
Start locally.
弄清楚他们有没有见过类似的东西
And, just find out if they've ever seen anything like this.
也许我们还能向一个人打听这事
There might be someone else we can ask about this.
你们记得帮助揭露
Do you remember the priest
公羊门徒邪教的那个神父吗
who helped expose the Disciples of the Ram cult?
大概是十到十二年前的事
It would've been about 10 or 12 years ago--
-卡斯特纳神父  -对
- Father Kastner? - Yeah, you're right.
不过他不再是神父了  他退休一阵子了
Only it isn't "Father" Anymore, he's been retired for a while.
他曾试图帮助那些人
He tried to help those people.
试图理解他们为什么那样做
He tried to understand why they did what they did.
如果有谁能告诉我们这是什么
If anyone is going to be able to tell us what this is,
那就是他了
it's him.
卡斯特纳神父
Father Kastner.
我没听见车开进来
I didn't hear the car drive in.
有谁想吃个煎蛋饼吗
Would either of you care for an omelet?
我们出门前吃过早饭了
We had breakfast before we left home.
我是艾德·沃伦  这是我妻子洛琳
I'm Ed Warren, this is my wife Lorraine.
我手上沾了鸡屎
I have chicken shit on my hands.
谢谢
Thank you.
忘了你们看过这个吧
Forget you ever saw this.
你之前见过吗
You've seen it before?
不  但我见过类似的
No. But I've seen ones like it.
这个很复杂精妙  是非常邪恶的物件
This is sophisticated. It's a very nasty piece of work.
我不理解的是为什么
What I don't understand is... is why?
戴维  那个被附身的小男孩
David, the little boy who was possessed,
他没做错什么
he didn't do anything wrong.
为什么会有人盯上这家人
Why would someone target this family?
为什么
Why?
原因不重要
The "why" is irrelevant.
原因与这个撒旦崇拜者的一切理念相悖
The "Why" is counter to everything that the Satanist stands for.
他的目标只有混乱
His sole aim is chaos.
绝望是他的佳酿
His nectar is despair.
但肯定有人把它放到了他们房子底下
But someone had to put it under their house.
你能从这个图腾看出幕后黑手的什么特征
So, what does this tell you about the person who made it?
跟我来
Come with me.
我不想下去
I don't want to go down there.
这是什么
What is this?
是你们来此的原因
It's the reason you're here.
我在研究公羊门徒的时候收集了这些
I collected these while I was studying the Disciples of the Ram.
-你应该把这些都烧了  -我想过
- You should burn all this. - I've thought of it.
但我觉得把它们锁起来更安全
But I felt it was safer to keep them locked.
我喜欢亲自消除这些威胁
I like taking guns off the streets.
我想你不是用杜威十进制分类法
I don't suppose you have all these books organized
整理这些书的吧
using the Dewey Decimal System, do you?
不  不是
No. No. No, I do not.
你们寻找的线索可能在任何地方  或者
The clues you seek could be anywhere. Or, they...
根本不在这儿
Or, they may not be here at all.
艾德  不要
Ed, don't.
我研究这些人九年了
I studied these people for nine years.
他们用血祭崇拜撒旦和它的恶魔们
They worshipped Satan and his demons with blood sacrifice.
用丑恶的仪式玷污圣地
They defiled holy land with their obscene rituals,
并且犯下了亵渎上帝的罪行
and they committed acts of blasphemy...
而我永远也不会提起
which I shall never speak of.
但这些行为给了他们力量
But... these acts gave them power.
对门徒们的审判
The trial of the Disciples,
当时的首席检察官  他的妻子怀孕了
the lead prosecutor, his wife was pregnant.
门徒们全部被判有罪  几天后
A few days after the Disciples were all found guilty,
他的孩子早产了六个礼拜
his baby was born six weeks early,
心脏长在了身体外
with its heart outside of its body.
三个月后  他的妻子
Three months later, his wife committed suicide
躺在铁轨上自杀
by laying her neck on a railroad track.
一个高阶撒旦崇拜者绝不是可以轻视的对手
A master Satanist is not an adversary to be taken lightly.
我们知道有什么样的危险  比你想的更清楚
We know the dangers, better than you might think.
这个就要被判死刑的男孩
This boy, who's headed to the death chamber...
值得你们不惜一切代价去拯救吗
is saving him worth everything you have?
因为你们很可能会失去所有
Because that's what it may very well cost.
你到底要不要清理干净
So, you gonna clean it up, or what?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
怎么回事
What?
∮ 为我涂上你的颜色  亲爱的 ∮
∮ Color me your color, darling ∮
∮ 我知道你是谁 ∮
∮ I know who you are ∮
∮ 洗去你的颜色  孩子 ∮
∮ Come up off your color, child ∮
∮ 我知道你从哪来 ∮
∮ I know where you're coming ∮
∮ 我知道你是谁 ∮
∮ I know who you are ∮
它刚才在这  我发誓  它刚才在这
It was here! I swear to God, it was here!
(沃伦)
看看佩伦一家送了什么来
Look what the Perron family sent.
他们还真贴心
Oh, that was sweet of them.
-我去接  -艾德  我来吧
- I got it. - Ed, let me.
没关系  没关系
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
-喂  -艾德
- Hello? - Ed?
我们有线索了
We've got a bite.
我刚跟丹佛市的一位凶杀案警探通过电话
I just got off the phone with a homicide detective in Danvers,
他想跟你们谈谈  他说他见过
he wants to talk to you guys. He says he says he's seen it.
(马萨诸塞州  丹佛市)
(寻人启事  杰西卡·露易丝·斯特朗)
凯蒂·林肯和杰西卡·斯特朗四个月前失踪了
Katie Lincoln and Jessica Strong went missing about four months ago.
她们在高中是最好的朋友
They were best friends in high school.
凯蒂的尸体在这附近被找到  被捅了二十二刀
Katie's body was found near here, stabbed 22 times.
我们至今没找到杰西卡
We still haven't found Jessica.
但当我们在五月搜查她的家时
But when we searched her home back in May...
我们发现了这个
we found this.
你们是专家
So, you're the experts.
关于这个你们能告诉我什么
What can you tell me about this?
老实说  很有限
Well, to be honest, not much.
只能说  如果这个图腾
Only that if this totem
跟布鲁克菲尔德的那个原理一样
works the same way as the one in Brookfield,
那失踪的女孩有可能是被附身了
it's possible that your missing girl was possessed.
听着  我读过
Look, I've read all about
你们对于布鲁克菲尔德发生的事的看法
what you two think happened in Brookfield.
但我只在乎基于现实的线索
But I'm only interested in leads that are grounded in reality.
很好  我们也是
Good. So are we.
其实我们希望
We were actually hoping
这案件资料里的内容
there might be something in this case file
能帮助证明阿尔尼的情况
that might help prove Arne's story.
不不不  我叫你们来是为了帮我
No, no, no. I brought you here to help me,
而不是反过来
not the other way around.
自从我们找到了那个东西之后
Now, we've been looking for a link to some sort of
就一直在寻找与某种邪教的联系
satanic cult ever since we found that thing.
这些恶魔崇拜者  他们只是人类
And these devil-worshippers, they're just people.
确实疯狂且邪恶  但只是人罢了
Crazy, evil people, but, people.
也许我们能够互相帮助
Maybe we can help each other.
我们需要看你们的案件资料
We need to see your casefile...
而你需要找到那个失踪的女孩
and you need to find the missing girl.
所以  给我们个机会吧
So, give us a chance.
-给你们机会做什么  -找到杰西卡
- To do what exactly? - To find Jessica.
我们已经在这片森林里
We've been combing through these forests
搜查三个多月了  沃伦太太
for over three months now, Mrs. Warren.
我能看到你们看不到的东西
I can see things that your people can't.
其中一把刀
One of these
是杀害凯蒂·林肯的凶器
is the knife used on Katie Lincoln.
另外两把是我从证物柜里随便拿的
The others I just pulled from the evidence locker.
怎么  你想让她选出哪一把是凶器吗
And what? You want her to pick out the murder weapon?
我会带你们去案发现场
I'll take you out there,
但我要先看看她的能力
but first I want to see what she can do.
绝对不行
Absolutely not!
我妻子的天赋可不是什么助兴节目
My wife's gift is not a sideshow attraction.
如果她真像你说的那么神
If she is what you say she is,
那这对她来说就是小事
then this shouldn't be a problem,
对不对  沃伦先生
Mr. Warren. Right?
-不行  别想了  我们...  -是这一把
- No way! Forget it. We-- - It's this one.
不过就是三分之一的概率罢了
It was a one-in-three chance.
这首歌挺合适的
This song's appropriate.
我其实见过猫王一次
You know, I actually met Elvis once.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
-是在他生前还是死后  -生前
- Was that before or after he died? - Before...
死后也见过
and after.
你忘记转弯了
You missed a turn.
你们找到凯蒂尸体的地方是在刚才那边
The spot where you found Katie's body, it was back that way.
他们现在在丹佛市
They're in Danvers, right now.
如果他们能找到办法
If they can find some way to
把那里的案子和你的经历联系起来  那么
connect what happened there to what happened to you, then...
就能找到规律
You know, it's... it's a pattern.
他们甚至有可能找到罪魁祸首
They might even find out who did this.
好吧  听上去真棒  是吧
Okay. Well, that sounds great, right?
-真棒  -亲爱的
- It's great. - Baby...
你怎么了
What's going on?
没事
Nothing.
我很好  就是累了
I'm fine, I'm tired, you know--
得了吧
Come on.
你有事情瞒着我
You're keeping something from me.
你觉得我看不出来吗
Don't you think I can tell that?
我很好  特别好
Look, I'm fine. Totally fine.
这里面好冷
It's cold in here.
是啊
Yeah, right?
就好像他们想要冻死我们似的
It's like, they're trying to freeze us out, or something.
我记得那种感觉
I remember what it felt like.
总是觉得冷  而且总有东西在跟着你
You're always cold, and you're never alone.
戴维  你在说什么
David, what are you talking about?
所以你无法入睡
That's why you can't sleep.
因为你的脑中总是不能安静下来
Because it's never quiet in your head.
有时候你会思考一些事
Sometimes you think something,
但你又不确定那是不是你自己的想法
then you're not sure if it was really you.
但是现在你能看到它了
But now you're seeing it.
它总是在你左右  叫你去做一些事
It's here with you. And it's telling you to do things.
阿尔尼  它让你做什么事
Arne, what is it telling you to do?
你确定要这样拄着拐杖在森林里走吗
You sure you should be tromping through the woods like this?
嗯  我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
那你在担心什么
Then what are you worried about?
你是担心她做不到吗
Afraid she won't be able to do it?
不是
No.
我是担心她会成功
I'm afraid that she will.
艾德  这里发生过可怕的事
Ed, something terrible happened here.
凯蒂  等等我
Katie, wait up.
我有东西要送给你
I got you something.
有人在今年的五月节上卖这个
They were selling them at the May Festival this year.
你父母还拉你去五月节呢
Your parents still dragging you up there for that?
从我六岁开始  每年都去
Every year, since I was six.
那里挺蠢的  但是我觉得这个很酷
It's dumb, but, I thought this was cool.
让我想起我们高中时一起编的那些
It reminded me of the ones we made in high school.
你帮我戴上好吗
Will you help me put it on?
当然
Sure.
好了  够了
All right, that's enough.
亲爱的  停下吧  够了  拜托
Hon, that's enough. That's enough! Come on!
凯蒂  凯蒂  我的天啊  我干了什么
Katie? Katie? Oh, my God. What did I do?
亲爱的  不要
Hon, no!
洛琳
Lorraine!
Lorraine.
艾德
Ed.
不要
No!
没事了  我抓住你了
It's okay. I got you. I got you.
她在下面
She's down there.
艾德  她在悬崖下面
Ed, she's down there.
血压有点高
Blood pressure's a little high.
我给你一片血管舒张药
I'm gonna give you a vasodilator.
你要把这药片含在舌头下面
It's a pill, you're gonna put it under your tongue.
能够帮助扩张你的血管
It'll open up your blood vessels.
好的  我有这种药
Yeah, I have those.
落在家里了
I left them at home.
好吧  我要是你的话下次肯定长记性
Yeah, well, I wouldn't do that anymore if I were you.
能让我们单独谈一谈吗
Mind giving us a minute?
搜救队找到了一具尸体
Recovery team found a body.
-是不是...  -还不确定
- Is it-- - We're not sure.
我知道看上去可能性很大
Look, I know what it looks like.
但是在验尸官验明尸体身份之前
But, I don't want any of this
我不希望关于此案的任何消息
getting out until we have a positive ID
被公之于众
from the coroner.
我们在这片水域搜寻过两次
You know, we dragged this basin. Twice.
要搜寻第三次真的挺困难的
Had to pull teeth to get it done a third time.
如果不是你们帮忙  我们根本做不到
We never would've done it if it weren't for you.
很高兴我们能帮上忙
I'm just glad we could help.
告诉我你们的住处
Let me know where you're staying.
明早我会把案件资料给你们送去
And I'll get that casefile to you in the morning.
(布鲁尼奥旅馆)
喂
Hello?
我的天  我打了一天的电话都没人接
Oh, my God, I've been leaving messages all day.
-出什么事了  -是阿尔尼  它跟上他了
- What's wrong? - It's Arne. It followed him!
你说过一切都结束了
You said this was over,
但是现在他和那个东西被困在里面
but now he's trapped in there with this thing
它正在教唆他自杀
and it's telling him to kill himself!
黛比
Debbie.
冷静下来听我说
Just calm down and listen to me.
我要你给监狱的牧师打电话
I need you to call the prison chaplain, um...
-纽曼神父  -对  纽曼神父  告诉他
- Father Newman. - Father Newman. Tell him that
阿尔尼需要接受全天候自杀监视  他有...
Arne needs to be put on a 24-hour suicide watch! He's got--
什么  听得见吗
What? Hello?
这到底是什么东西
What is this thing?
阿尔尼
Arne.
上帝给予每个人保护自己的权利
God gives everyone the right to defend themselves.
这个恶魔
This demon...
不是它自己想来的  它是被召唤来的
it's not here of its own free will. It was summoned.
这话并不能让我好受些
That doesn't make me feel any better.
这意味着  我们知道这是个诅咒
That means, we know that this is a curse,
而诅咒是可以被打破的
and curses can be broken.
好吧  那我们怎么做
All right. Then, how do we do that?
在格拉策尔家时
Back at the Glatzel house,
我碰到了戴维的手  看到了一些画面
I touched David's hand and I saw something.
当时我不知道那是什么
I didn't know what it was then.
但现在我认为
But I think that I was connected
我是和罪魁祸首连接到了一起
to the person who is responsible for this.
艾德  他们找到的那具尸体
Ed, that body they found...
如果那真的是杰西卡
if it's Jessica, if it's really her,
那么这个连接应该可以被再次打开
then that connection could still be open.
一定还有别的方法
There's gotta be another way.
好了  没事的
Okay... okay.
好了
Okay.
耶和华是我的牧者
The Lord is my shepherd,
我必不至缺乏
there is nothing I shall want.
他使我躺卧在青草地上
He maketh me to lie down in green pastures...
(帕尔默里殡仪馆)
里面没人
There's nobody there.
留张纸条就行了
We'll leave a note.
天啊
Oh, boy.
(丹佛市警察局  无名氏)
求你千万小心点
Please be careful.
你看到什么了吗
Do you see anything?
没有  什么也没看见
No. There's nothing.
这里什么也没有
There's nothing here.
我感知不到
I'm not sensing it.
-洛琳  怎么了  -是连接
- Lorraine, what is it? - The connection.
连接在这里
It's here.
你看到什么了吗
Do you see anything?
是的
Yes.
我看到了一些台阶
Yes, there are... some stairs.
我听到火车的声音
I heard a train.
但是现在
But now...
我看到了祭坛
there's an altar.
有好多黑色的蜡烛
All those black candles.
十二支蜡烛摆成了一个圈
There's 12 of them. In a circle.
艾德
Oh, Ed.
好了  够了  回来吧
Okay, that's enough, come back.
不行
I can't.
洛琳
Lorraine.
是个女人
It's a woman.
你能看到她的长相吗
Can you see her?
此刻我就是她
I am her.
你能看出她在哪里吗
Can you tell where she is?
我不知道  我...
I don't know. I...
她又开始了
She's doing it again.
她在连接阿尔尼
She's reaching out to Arne.
她想要完成这个诅咒
She's trying to complete the curse.
她控制住他了  她控制了阿尔尼
Oh, she has him. She has Arne.
不  不要
Oh, no, no.
不  不  天啊
No, no. Oh, God.
终止这黑色安息日
End this black sabbath.
我以受难耶稣之血命令你
By the blood of Calvary I command it!
有犯人割腕了  C19房
I got a cutter! C-19!
振作点  孩子
Come on, kid.
你怎么做到的
How are you doing this?
上帝令我看见你的
God has shown you to me.
那你的上帝诅咒了你
Then your God has damned you.
艾德  这个连接是双向的
Ed. The connection works both ways.
洛琳
Lorraine.
你得醒过来
You need to come back.
洛...
Lorr...
洛琳
Lorraine?
你得断开连接
You need to break the connection.
放开她的手
Drop her hand.
洛琳  放开她的手
Lorraine, let go of her hand.
艾德
Ed...
她知道我们是谁了
She knows who we are.
(沃伦)
真抱歉
We are so sorry.
我们真的很抱歉
Oh, we're so sorry.
阿尔尼怎么样了
How's Arne?
他会没事的  他们给他打了镇定剂
He'll be all right. They got him sedated.
我们拿到案件资料了
We got the casefile.
这里面一定能找到
There's got to be something here
那两个女孩和阿尔尼的联系
that connects these girls back to him.
太好了
That's great.
我也有东西要给你们看
I got something to show you, too.
我在意大利巫术书里找到这个
I found it in the Stregheria.
是在文艺复兴早期
It's early Renaissance.
教会利用它来识别并迫害巫术
The Church used it to identify and persecute witchcraft.
我拉丁语有点生疏了
Now... my Latin is rusty,
但我觉得这段
but... I think this...
讲的是活人祭祀
is talking about a human sacrifice.
一个被杀  一个自杀
One by murder and the other by suicide.
书里有说怎么停止这个仪式吗
Does it say how to stop it?
有  好像...
Yeah, it looks like...
可以通过摧毁施咒祭坛来打破诅咒
you can break the curse by destroying the altar it was cast from.
不过
But...
这段好像是用阿拉米语写的
this part looks like Aramaic.
下面这段我看不懂
This next part, I can't read it.
但你打断她了  说不定她会放弃
But you stopped her. Maybe she'll give up now.
她不能放弃
She can't.
一旦开始  诅咒就必须完成
Once started, the curse must be completed.
她赌上了她的灵魂
Her soul depends on it.
我们会找到别的办法的
We'll find another way.
你看到的幻象里
Was there anything in your vision
有没有什么线索能帮我们找到她的祭坛
that might help us find her altar?
那里很冷
It was cold.
天花板上有水滴下来
There was water dripping from the ceiling.
我好像听到了火车声
I think I heard a train.
但声音听起来很奇怪  就像
But it sounded strange somehow. Like, um...
我说不好  模糊不清
I don't know, muffled?
可能那地方在地下
Well, maybe it was underground.
有可能  不知道是哪里的地下
Could be. I don't know where.
这个女人盯上戴维和杰西卡
This woman targeted David and Jessica.
或许他们两人有什么联系
Maybe there's a connection there.
我去看看...
Let me take a look at the...
看看...
Take a look at the...
案件资料
file.
洛琳
Lorraine?
Lorraine!
她在哪里
Where is she?
你们的收藏还挺有趣的
You know, the two of you have gathered quite the collection.
你要是伤害她
If you hurt her...
别担心  沃伦先生
Oh, don't worry, Mr. Warren.
你非常接近了
You're so close.
现在放弃就太可惜了
I'd hate for you to give up now.
命海水来浇到地上的人
He who calls forth the water of the sea!
耶和华是祂的名
The Lord of Hosts is His name!
解救你的仆人
Deliver Thy servant
脱离污灵的控制
from all the workings of unclean spirits!
恐惧吧  逃走吧  污灵
Fear and flee, unclean spirit!
艾德
Ed!
Ed.
对不起
I'm sorry.
艾德  是她干的
Ed, it was her!
是她干的
It was her.
-艾德  到底怎么回事  -帮我找到它
- Ed, what the hell is going on? - Help me find it!
找什么
Find what?
在哪里
Where is it?
艾德
Ed.
Ed!
她来过这里  她来过我们家里
She was here! She was in our house!
这些花是什么时候送来的
When did these get here?
昨天才送来
They just arrived yesterday
你们当时在回家路上
while you guys were driving home.
送到的时候都还很新鲜
They were fresh when they got here.
我们得找到这个女人
We have to find this woman.
我们已经确认了这是诅咒
We've identified the curse
现在手里又有杰西卡的案件资料
and now we have Jessica's casefile.
里面一定有什么线索
There has to be something in here.
我带上书去找人翻译
Okay, I'm gonna take the book to be translated.
书里一定有指引我们找到祭坛的线索
There has to be a clue about where we can find the altar.
那我们能做什么
So what do we do?
你应该去陪着阿尔尼
You should go be with Arne.
他今晚最需要你在身边
He's gonna need you tonight more than ever.
找纽曼神父帮忙
Ask Father Newman for help.
德鲁  我们研究那些案件资料
Drew, you and me are gonna tear into those files.
一定要找出两起案子之间的联系
We've got to find a link between these cases.
撒旦崇拜者的力量在夜里最强大  所以
And a Satanist's power is strongest at night. So...
但愿她在夜幕降临前不要有所行动
Let's hope she doesn't try anything before then.
他们已经把镇定剂停了
They've stopped his sedation.
他很快就会清醒过来
He'll be coming around soon.
这些笔录里什么线索都没有
There's nothing in these interviews.
她从大学回来后  朋友们几乎都没见过她
Her friends barely saw her after she got back from college.
你不觉得奇怪吗
Didn't that seem strange to you?
我们在这里
I mean, we're here,
格拉策尔家在这里  只有十五分钟车距
the Glatzels live here, just 15 minutes away.
但杰西卡住在180英里之外
But Jessica lived 180 miles from here.
为什么她在那么远的地方
Why is this one so far away?
杰西卡在哪里发现图腾的
Hey, where did Jessica find her totem?
我刚看到过
I just saw something about that.
在对她父母的询问笔录里
It was in an interview with her parents.
是在一个盒子里
It was in a box.
"她把图腾装在一个盒子里  从大学带回家"
"She brought it back home in a box from college."
她在哪里上的大学
Where'd she go to college?
费尔菲尔德市
Fairfield.
这个女人就住在这一带
This woman lives in the area.
搜寻范围还是很大
Still a lot of ground to cover.
对  但这里火车轨道并不多
Yeah, but not a lot of train tracks.
记得洛琳看到的幻象吗  她说听到火车声
Remember Lorraine's vision? She said she heard a train.
当时是几点
What time was it?
或许我们可以排除一些线路
Maybe we can start eliminating some of these.
应该是临近午夜
Probably close to midnight.
那就不可能是这两条线路
Then it can't be either of these two.
通勤线路不会开到那么晚
The commuter lines don't run that late.
那就只剩这条货运线了
That just leaves this freight line
跨河的
that crosses the river here.
河
The river.
天啊
Oh, dear God.
沃伦太太
Mrs. Warren.
真抱歉  神父  我们打过电话
I'm sorry, Father, we tried calling,
但是没人接
but we couldn't reach you.
我们想请你帮忙翻译一段书里的话
We were hoping you'd help us translate a passage from this book.
当然可以  请进
Of course. Come in.
谢谢
Thank you.
车钥匙给我  你留在这里  报警
Give me your keys. You stay here, call the police.
我怎么跟他们说
What do you want me to tell them?
随便说什么  能让他们出警就行
Anything, just get 'em out there!
这是讲诅咒的
It's the curse.
书上说  需要三个受害者才能完成诅咒
It says, the curse needs three victims to be complete.
书里把他们称为
It refers to them as...
"孩子  爱人和圣徒"
"The child, the lover and the man of God."
他们是上帝之作的化身
The embodiment of God's work.
纯洁  爱  信仰
Purity, love, faith.
又发现新的受害者了吗
Has there been another?
是艾德  我丈夫
It's Ed. It's my husband.
昨晚我们在他办公室里发现了一个图腾
Last night we found a totem in his office.
太不幸了
That is unfortunate.
来  跟我来
Here, come with me.
我有东西要给你看
There's something I need to show you.
神父
Father?
我在这里住了很多年了
I've been here many years...
从还是牧师的时候开始
starting when I was a priest.
教堂把这座磨坊当作储藏室
The church used this mill for storage.
用来存放那些他们惧怕的东西
It's where they put the things that they were afraid of.
他们不理解的东西
Things they didn't understand.
(伊思拉  三个月  1932年)
你有过一个孩子
You had a child?
她母亲死于难产
Her mother died in childbirth.
我不能让教会知道
The Church couldn't know.
所以我偷偷地把她养在这里
So I raised her here, in secret.
我们两个相依为命
It was just the two of us.
(1952年  八月)
整间屋子都洋溢着幸福
Our happiness filled this house.
我继续研究这些神秘学
I continued my studies into the occult.
我本来想要让她远离这些东西
I wanted to protect her from all this.
但相反她却为此着迷
Instead I created a fascination.
我们一定要小心
We must be careful
孩子会继承我们的痴迷
how our obsessions are passed to our children.
"住在至高者隐密处的
"He who dwells in the shelter of the most high
必住在全能者的荫下
will rest in the shadow of the Almighty.
我要论到耶和华说
I will say of the Lord,
他是我的避难所  是我的山寨
He is my refuge and my fortress,
是我的神  是我所信靠的"
my God, in whom I trust."
线路问题而已
It's just the wiring.
你懂的  政府建筑
You know, state building.
黛比
Debbie.
阿尔尼
Arne.
怎么了
What is it?
她...她就在附近
She's... she's close.
你早知道了
You knew?
我们来向你求助  其实你从一开始就知道了
We came to you for help and you knew this whole time?
她是我的女儿
She's my daughter.
我无法...
I couldn't...
我不想看透
I didn't want to see.
过了这么多年
After all these years,
我以为她终于再回到我身边
I thought she'd come back to me again.
现在我知道她来这的真正原因了
And now I know the real reason she's here.
这片土地底下有隧道
There are tunnels under this land.
她小时候经常在里面探索
She would explore them as a child.
她的祭坛一定就在这下面
Her altar must be down there.
这是唯一能打破她诅咒的东西
It's the only thing that can break her curse.
我们必须摧毁祭坛
We need to destroy it.
她来了
She's here.
快去
Go.
我是个失职的牧师
I failed as a priest.
也是个失职的父亲
And I failed as a father.
求求你  上帝  别让我也失败...
Please, God, don't let me fail--
洛琳
Lorraine!
艾德
Ed!
洛琳
Lorraine!
艾德
Ed?
Ed!
洛琳
Lorraine!
艾德
Ed!
看着我
Look at me.
睁开眼睛
Open your eyes.
看着我
Look at me.
不
No!
看着我
Look at me.
睁开眼睛  看着我
Open your eyes and look at me.
快睁眼
Open up.
洛琳
Lorraine!
Lorraine?
艾德
Ed!
Ed?
艾德
-要发生了  -现在吗
- It's happening. - Now?
现在
Now.
艾德  住手
Ed, stop!
住手  艾德  求你了
Stop! Ed, I'm begging you!
艾德  住手
Ed! Stop!
阿尔尼
Arne!
阿尔尼  求你  没事的
Arne, please. It's okay.
我们在天上的父
Our Father who art in heaven
- 愿人都尊你的名为圣  -不  阿尔尼  没事的
- hallowed be thy name... - No, Arne. It's okay! Please!
愿你的国降临  愿你的旨意行在地上
thy kingdom come, thy will be done...
-如同行在天上  -阿尔尼  没事的
- on earth as it is in heaven. - Arne, it's okay!
住手  艾德  我求你了
Stop this! Ed, I'm begging you!
求求你  想起我
I'm begging you, remember me!
住手
Stop!
艾德  住手
Ed, stop!
艾德  求你
Ed, please.
想起我
Remember me.
天啊  警卫
Oh, my God! Guards!
...不叫我们遇见试探
And lead us not into temptation
救我们脱离凶恶
but deliver us from evil.
-我因为国度...  -阿尔尼  没事的
- For thine is the kingdom... - Arne, it's okay.
权柄  荣耀...
...the power and the glory...
直到永远  阿门
...now and forever, amen!
我们在天上的父  愿人都尊你的名为圣
Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed by thy name,
愿你的国降临  愿你的旨意行在地上
thy kingdom come, thy will be done
-如同行在天上  -不  阿尔尼
- on earth as it is in heaven. - No, Arne!
阿尔尼  阿尔尼  你要干什么
Arne? Arne, what are you doing?
你要干什么  住手
What are you doing? Stop it!
你要干什么  纽曼神父  帮帮他
What are you doing? Father Newman, help him!
求求你  警卫
Please... Guards!
求你  住手
Please! Stop it!
拜托你帮帮他
Please help him!
你不会这么做的
You're not gonna do this!
这是错的  你心里明白
This is wrong and you know it!
纽曼神父  不  不
Father Newman... No, no.
这是怎么回事
What's happening?
神父  让他停下来
Please, Father, make it stop!
我们在天上的父  愿人都尊你的名为圣
Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name,
愿你的国降临
thy kingdom come...
不  不  阿尔尼  不
No, no, no! Arne, no!
阿尔尼  住手  求你住手
Arne, stop, please! Stop it!
别这么做  阿尔尼  我爱你
Don't do this, Arne, I love you!
不
No...
不叫我们遇见试探
And lead us not into temptation,
救我们脱离凶恶
but deliver us from evil!
艾德  想起我
Ed... Remember me.
她想让你和我反目成仇
She tried to turn you against me.
因为她认为你我之间的爱是我们的弱点
Because, she thinks our love is our weakness.
但并非如此
But it's not.
并非如此
It's not.
爱是我们的力量
It's our strength.
睁开眼睛吧
Now, open your eyes.
阿尔尼  阿尔尼  你没事吧
Arne? Arne, are you okay?
天啊
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
你的诅咒被打破了
Your curse is broken.
你承诺了恶魔  会献上一个灵魂
You promised a demon a soul.
不得到  它是不会回地狱的
And it can't go back to hell without one.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
没事了  结束了
It's okay. It's over.
告诉我都结束了
Please say it's over...
亲爱的  我...
Hon... I...
我忘带药了
I forgot my pills.
阿尔尼
Arne?
让一下  阿尔尼
Excuse me. Arne!
我爱你
I love you.
请被告起立
Will the defendant please rise?
(1981年11月24日  阿尔尼·约翰逊被判过失杀人罪名成立)
(阿尔尼服刑五年  他在狱中和黛比完婚)
(他们至今仍是夫妻)
我们现在回顾此事时  听着录音
As we go back now, listen to the tapes
犹如身处现场  听见他动手
as well as being there and hearing him do it,
他会不断地质疑  那男孩体内的到底是什么
he would constantly challenge what was in that boy.
那对整个
What does that do
-法律体系会有什么影响  -是的
- to the whole system of law... - Yes.
如果一个人可以在庭上辩称
...if a person can walk in and say,
"是恶魔逼我做的"
"The devil made me do it"?
戴维  我要把这个放在你身上
David, I'm going to put this on you.
奉耶稣之名  耶稣驱逐你
In the name of Jesus, Jesus repels you.
远离这个孩子
Leave this child alone.
在你额头上
It's on your forehead.
(1981年2月16日  阿尔尼·约翰逊谋杀案)
记住  你并不强大  你很软弱
Yes, remember, you are not strong, you're weak.
你很软弱
You're weak.
耶稣爱这男孩  这是祂的孩子
Jesus loves this boy. This is... this is His child.
让他清醒过来  扶他起来  想想办法
Wake him out of it. Prop him up. Do something!
他现在摆脱不了  妈妈
He won't get out of it right now, Ma.
他辱骂我  你却什么也没做
Well he called me names, you didn't do nothing now!
你以为我们一直以来在干什么
Well, what do you think we've been doing all this time?
以圣父  圣子
In the name of the Father and the Son
和圣灵的名义  阿门
and the Holy Spirit, amen!
(法官  陪审团和神秘学)
你得摁住他  他叫我这么做的
You gotta hold him down. He told me to.
把他摁在地上
Hold him on the ground.
妈妈在这里  妈妈在这里
Mommy's here. Mommy's here.
快醒醒
Come on, wake up.
快起来  我们走
Come on. Get up. Come on, let's go.
滚出去  从我儿子体内滚出去
Get out. Get out of my son.
从我儿子体内滚出去  快
Get out of my son. Come on.
撑住  儿子  滚出去  远离我儿子
Come on, son. Come on. Get out. Get away from my son.
快啊  不
Go on! No!
我是你的母亲
I'm your mother!
不  你是...
No, you're...
戴维  戴维  醒醒啊
David. David. Wake up!
放开这男孩
Let the boy go.
听着  你得摁住他
Look, you need to hold him.
以圣父
In the name of the Father
圣子和圣灵的名义  阿门
and the Son and of the Holy Spirit. Amen.
想想办法  扶他坐起来
Do something. Sit him up.
-没用的  -不能扶他坐起来
- It won't work. - You can't sit him up, he's...
没用的
It won't work.
妈妈  你死了
Mom, you're dead!
(1981年  康涅狄格州  布鲁克菲尔德)
戴维  快起来
David! Please, get up!
天啊  起来
My God! Get up!